to order. The board of adjustment uh
meeting of April 16, 2026 is now in
session. Would you please do the roll
call?
>> Dustin Brown.
>> Charity Campfield here.
>> Curtis Claybaw here. Michael O'Donnell
>> here.
>> Erin Leblink
>> here. Linda Burke
>> here.
>> Chair, you have a quorum.
>> And I think we have a quorum. So I will
go ahead and um ask if everyone's had a
chance to read the minutes from the our
last meeting which was February 19th.
>> Move to approve.
>> Is there a second?
>> I'll second.
It's been moved and seconded that the
meetings be uh the meeting minutes be
approved. Um
is there a vote please? All those all
those in favor please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> Thank you.
Um
we have one request. Would you like to
read that request please?
Item A, request PUDC-26-56,
conditional use request to allow multif
family within the MR zone located at
3115 Dylan Avenue. The agent is Brandon
Swain and the case planner is Morgan
Dennis.
>> Thank you. Um, is there anyone here that
would like to testify uh on this
this report in support? Thank you.
Oh, staff report first.
>> Oh, thank you. Staff report first.
Okay. And I actually had that written.
Madame Chair, members of the board,
Morgan Dennis Planning and Development.
Um, this is a conditional use request to
allow multi-dwelling buildings at 3115
Dylan Avenue. This parcel is located in
the MR medium density residential zone
district and is surrounded by additional
MR zones.
The future land use map designates this
area as urban residential, a designation
that promotes a variety of residential
types.
Currently, there are two structures
existing on the property. a house which
has been granted an administrative
adjustment to decrease the required
frontage for SD3
lot to allow for a duplex on the lot and
a detached garage.
Currently, there are no submitted plans
to remove either of these existing
structures. The applicant is only
requesting an additional unit. It is
noted that an approval of this use for
this parcel would classify this parcel
as an MD3
lot type, which allows for a building to
be to be three stories tall or five
stories with conditional review.
Surrounding structures are primarily
one-story single family residential
houses. There is a multi-dwelling
development to the west of this site
that stands at two stories.
Operating characteristics would be in
line with the surrounding area. Traffic
patterns are expected to be similar as
any residential development with
existing alley access and parking area
in the rear. Front or on street parking
would not be appropriate for the
property.
Staff has received concerns from
neighbors in regards to parking and
potential developments of a larger
multi-dwelling development.
It was explained that the applicant has
expressed that they were only adding a
single residential development to the
site and parking would likely be likely
be delegated to the rear of the property
through a potential site plan.
Staff is recommending a few conditions
for this property for this use.
First is to keep the number of dwelling
units allowed on the property to be
three. Second, any structure constructed
would be limited to two stories. And
lastly, all residential parking for the
property shall be located in the rear
with alley access. And uh I stand for
questions. Thank you. Are there any
questions?
>> Madam chair, I do have a couple.
>> Yes, please.
>> Morgan, can you help me with the the
picture? The existing structure is a
duplex already. Is that right?
>> The existing u madam chair through you.
Um the existing structure is a
technically a single family uh dwelling.
That is what the Larry County assessor
has um classified it as, but they have
gone through the administrative
adjustment process through our office to
allow that that um prop that structure
to be a duplex.
>> All right. So, it's not yet a duplex.
>> It's not yet. Not to our knowledge.
>> And then the third structure is going to
go somewhere in the backyard there. Is
that right?
>> Um
staff is unaware of that plan. that
exact plan. Um, I would leave that to
the applicant to explain.
>> I'll talk to the applicant. Thanks a
lot.
>> Are there any other questions?
>> All right. Thank you. Um, is there
anyone here for from the applicant to uh
talk about this testify on this
particular application?
>> Would you state your name and your
address, please?
>> Yes. Uh, Madam Chair, uh, members of the
board of adjustment, good evening.
Brandon Swain, agent for the applicant,
um, 3201 Cheyenne Street.
>> Uh, and would you raise your right hand,
please?
>> Yes.
>> And do you swear to tell the truth and
only the truth in this matter under
consideration before the board?
>> Yes.
>> Thank you. Go ahead, please.
>> Great. Um, so first off, Morgan, thank
you. That was a great presentation. Um,
just to be mindful of your time. I don't
have much more to add, just a few
clarifications. Uh the applicant is
agreeable to all the conditions set
forth. Our intention is only to add one
unit. Uh so of course we're agreeable to
cap this at three. Um did try to put
that this was pursuing a three-unit
building and the notification letter. Um
but we needed to amend that to a multif
family dwelling. So I do apologize to
some of the neighbors if the perception
is that we're going to exceed more than
three units. We're not. Uh they're also
agreeable to the uh parking in the rear.
Uh to answer Mr. For O'Donnell's
question, uh, we're not quite sure on
how the third unit is going to be
constructed. I'm assuming it's likely
going to be reconfigured in the basement
because the nature of doing an addition
or significant remodel of this scope is
likely going to trigger the existing
dwelling into current code compliance,
which is very difficult to do with these
houses that are uh built nearly 100
years ago. I will speak for the
applicant. Um, they are Lindb's houses.
Uh they have a tremendous track record
track record, excuse me, cleaning up
dilapidated properties throughout the
city. They've also grown a very strong
rental portfolio. Um so I expect good
tenants uh tenants who are mindful uh
and high expectations from the landlord
on any future tenants in this building.
That being said, I stand for any
questions.
>> Thank you, Madam Chair. Brandon, so am I
tracking you that this is going to
become a 3plex, you believe? Yes. Yes.
So, the the nature of the zone district
and would invite staff to interject at
any time if I'm incorrect. Um, but the
zone district does allow duplex use by
right. So, any lot in the zone district,
assuming that it meets the frontage
requirements, uh, is inherently allowed
to do a duplex. Uh, there are, um, lot
with minimums that are required within
the UDC. Um, so I'm not surprised that
the applicant had previously seek
administrative adjustment uh to allow
that reduced frontage. Um, because the
nature of these lots and houses is that
they were just platted smaller. Uh, and
then I I think their intention is to
explore the third unit because they do
have abundant parking um along the rear
alley. If it is a third unit and it's
inside of the basement, it's likely
going to be a one-bedroom unit which
only requires one parking space within
the UDC. Uh so my perception in that of
the applicant is we should be able to
accommodate plenty of the parking rear
loaded. Uh they they were prepared to
offer a front-loaded driveway if need
be. Um but it seems to be that staff's
expectation is that all the parking is
facilitated in the rear.
>> All right. Thank you. You're welcome.
>> Are there other questions?
Please.
>> So my question is you have one existing
structure you're turning to a duplex.
You're wanting to add a second structure
on the lot. Is the plan to eventually
subdivide the plat to separate the two
buildings?
>> Uh, no. And if I may clarify, Madam
Chair, through you, um, I I don't know
for certain that the third unit will be
in addition. Um, I suspect in in my
experience, which I have quite a bit
with these info properties, is it's
probably not equitable to build a new
third unit to run its own water and
sewer, likely have it separately
metered. Um, so my assumption is that
they're likely going to try and
accomplish the third unit within the
basement of the building. However, I
will entertain a hypothetical scenario.
If they did build a unit on the south
half of the lot, for lack of a better
term, that appears vacant, uh, that
would result in a non-conforming
property if they ever tried to plat
that, um, I believe the minimum frontage
that you can have for a single family
dwelling is 30 ft. That would be likely
a DD8 lot type, which is an NR3 zone.
Uh, so they would have to reszone this.
every neighbor neighbor, excuse me,
every neighbor would get a letter,
multiple hearings through city council,
public service committee, and even if
that made it, it's still a
non-conforming lot with frontage. Uh,
and Mr. O'Donnell will will testify.
I've done some pretty aggressive
projects, but that would be too
aggressive. Um, so I suspect that uh
this will not entertain any future plat
action.
>> Other questions?
I have a question. Um, in looking at
that lot, uh, there is a separate unit
on the back of that lot that is a
separate building, uh, from what I saw
when I drove by it. So, my question is,
does that building stay or did was I not
looking at the proper place? Also, it
seems like there's not a lot of room
back there for parking. I mean, it's a
small lot. So, do you know something
about that building in back and and that
building in back is lab labeled a studio
apartment and it's 3117?
>> Uh, so the madam chair through you the
the most honest answer is is I don't
know. Um, the I I assume that the back
unit was a detached garage which would
count for one parking space. Uh, the lot
is likely at least 35 to 36 ft wide. UDC
requires 8 1/2 ft minimum with for
parking. So my perception is that
whether that's a studio in the back or
an apartment, we're still able to
accomplish uh the uh satisfaction of
parking requirements with what the lot
frontage currently allows and then what
with what we can allow in the alley. But
I do apologize. I don't have a succinct
concise answer for you on that.
It it seems to me that maybe that
building at one point was a garage and
it was turned in to a small studio
apartment. Um, and I guess my concern uh
after looking at the area and the houses
is still parking, but uh is there anyone
else that would like to testify on the
application
>> in support?
>> Yes.
>> Of the application? Um I suspect not.
Um, I guess I'm cautiously optimistic
that there's others in the audience. Um,
I will clarify that if this motion
passes tonight, uh, and able to make
this legal and conforming to the
planning department, the applicant will
have to go through a site plan process
which will they have to indicate meeting
landscape requirements, setback
requirements, and parking requirements
as well.
>> All right. Thank you,
>> Madam Chair. Thank you.
>> All right. It's um time for public
comment. If there are individuals that
would from the public, would would you
please come up?
>> And would you give your name and
address, sir?
>> I'm sorry.
>> My name is Edward. My name is Edward
Henson and I live at 3121 Dylan Avenue.
U looking at the U. Before you go ahead,
would you please raise your right hand?
And do you swear to tell the truth and
only the truth in this matter under
consideration before the board? Thank
you.
>> Looking at the side plot, that building
you were talking about outback is a
detached garage.
>> The one you were talking a studio
apartment is the property next to it in
which then they have two apartments in
the building in front of it which is an
Abn essentially. So we get all kinds of
parking there from that. You assume one
car. Sometimes there's two cars per
place. Across the street at the multi-
family, the one that faces Randall,
their garages faces Dylan. There's a
minimum of eight cars just for a
forplex.
The multif family that's across the
street from me on Dylan. Their garages
are on day. They don't park in the
garages. They park on Dylan.
>> There's five cars for that. Um, you
know, it's just And then the the Airbnb,
like I said, it's even no bigger than
the house that they want to put a
triplex in. So, it's like how can you
put three places in that building?
>> And let me ask you a question now. When
you said there's an Airbnb, is that the
the house?
>> That's the 3117 Dylan.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> That's what that is.
>> Okay.
>> And so there's an upstairs, a
downstairs, and then that's out back.
All right.
>> And the parking situation just gets
worse every year because more and more
of these places are be being converted
into these multif family things,
>> essentially destroying the single family
house units around the neighborhood.
Um, I can just see a problem with
parking now. Plus, I was informed by at
one time with the city sanitation,
eventually our trash pickup is going to
move to the street, not the alley. So
then you're going to have that problem.
If you go in the alley where they're
saying the parking is, okay, they put a
triplex. Who has one car? Everybody has
two cars now. They're not going to be
able to put six cars back there. And
it's it's a narrow alley. It's rough.
It's going to get tore up even worse.
the city grades it maybe once or twice a
year is all. So I'm against it, you
know. I mean I can ever since we' lived
here, which is 1967 when my family moved
into that house, the only time I hadn't
lived there is my service in the in the
army. It's always been a single family
dwelling and now they want to expand it
to two or three. Doesn't make sense to
me.
>> Um, thank you, sir. Um, are there other
questions of this gentleman?
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you for your testimony.
Come on up.
And your name and address, please.
>> My name is Patrick Elvis. I live at 3213
Dylan Avenue.
>> And would you raise your right hand? Uh,
do you swear to tell the truth and only
the truth in this matter under
consideration by the board?
>> I do.
>> Thank you. Go ahead.
>> Um, I live at 3213. Um my number one con
concern is just the
the overall condition of the
neighborhood. Um there is no less than
12 to 14 multif family units on that
block of Dylan Avenue as it is. Um it
creates a very disongjoined
neighborhood. Um you end up with a lot
of people moving in and out continuously
continuously. Um, the property to the
north of me, it has a second unit in the
basement. Property uh directly west of
me has at least four units in it. And
then you have the multif family units,
which is eight total on Dylan. So, um,
and as Edward Ed said, um, there's three
units that Airbnb short-term rentals
right next door to this property of con
consideration.
um as a young family I have, you know,
child. I I would like to see a a more
conjoined neighborhood where um you
know, families can get together and get
to know each other um rather than
continually have um different people
moving in and out. So, parking is also
of concern cuz um the neighbor to the
north of me has no more than four
vehicles between the two people that
live there. Um the the four units um
across from me at believe that one is 32
um 14 Dylan. Um that is anywhere from
four to five vehicles as well on at that
place. Um and as more cars show up to
the south of our properties, it just
continues to get more and more
congested. So um those are my concerns.
Thank you. And uh does anyone have any
questions of this gentleman? Any other
questions? Thank you for your testimony,
sir.
Other individuals from the community,
public public comments, please come up.
>> Your name and address, please. And thank
you. Christina Sheileely, 3205 Dylan
Avenue.
>> And would you raise your right hand? And
do you swear to tell the truth and only
the truth in this matter under
consideration by the board?
>> I do.
>> Thank you.
>> I just wanted to let you guys know that
I understand both positions and I
understand the housing seriousness of
it. Um the parking is really, really bad
and during Frontier Days, it's an
absolute nightmare for everyone. You
wouldn't think all the way up at the
park, but they're all the way down in
front of our houses now. Um, at night
there is nowhere to park. They're
physically parking on other streets when
they live on our street. Um, even though
I do see both sides of it, my biggest
issue is the constant
traffic of humans in those Airbnbs. It
makes me nervous. They park illegally.
They do whatever they want. And they're
coming and going all night, all day. So
every day or two, day and night, there
are different people
who choose when to obey the traffic
laws. And it's creepy. So, even though I
see I understand both sides, I wanted to
tell you guys that because it's kind of
scary living there because of the
Airbnbs and the traffic and people not
not following the law all the time.
And that's all I wanted to tell you.
>> Any questions?
Thank you for your testimony.
Are there any other comments?
Right. At this point in time, I will
close the testimony. Um,
comments from the board.
>> You know, m Madam Chair, if I might, uh,
sort of as a point of order, what I
would propose doing is I'll make the
motion that's recommended by the staff.
>> Okay.
>> And hopefully get a second and then we
can have a conversation and we can
either
vote in favor of it or vote against it
on the positive motion. Sometimes when
you do a motion to deny, you end up
getting backwards.
>> Yes. Thank Thank you.
>> So if that if that's
>> absolutely appropriate. Sure.
>> I will move to approve the project
subject to staff's recommended
conditions.
>> Second.
>> All right. Thank you. Now we can have
some discussion.
>> All right. If I may on the motion,
please.
>> Um
>> good comments from everybody. Thank you
very much. Uh uh don't forget members of
the board that all we're doing at this
stage is approving a conditional use. It
must go through the site plan process
and all of the concerns that have been
raised by the folks in the audience have
to be addressed in the site plan
process. I just offer that out there. Uh
and I'll stand down. Thank you.
>> Thank you. That's an excellent point.
Other comments, please.
Basically, I was going to make the same
comment because I will be supporting the
staff recommendation for approval, but I
believe that through the site process,
the site plan, everything should be
addressed. So, the way it stands right
now may not be approved if they don't
comply. So, I do believe your concerns
will be addressed, but
we're really need to sort of back what
the recommendations are because those
are they met the legal requirements
as a minimum. So, I think we're sort of
forced to support that. They're not
violating. However, I do believe that
the process will shake it out at the
end.
>> Thank you. Other comments?
Are we ready for a vote?
>> Call for the question.
>> If you'd go ahead with the roll call.
>> Charity Campfield.
>> Yes.
>> Curtis Claybour.
>> Michael O'Donnell.
>> Hi.
>> Aaron Leink.
>> Yes.
>> Wend.
>> Chair. The motion passes.
>> Thank you. And I think we are now on to
any other business or any announcements.
>> I just wanted to also add with that last
um item. Currently the city does not
regulate Airbnbs at all. And so um we
don't have any regulations to deny any
type of Airbnb at this point in time.
And if that is something that um
neighbors are concerned about, they
should be speaking to their city council
members.
Good point. Thank you,
>> Madam Chair.
>> Yes.
>> May I ask Erin a question?
>> Sure.
>> In the annual review that city council
conducts of the code, are there Airbnb
provisions that are under consideration?
>> We don't have any at this time.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Thank you. I think that's a very good
point for people to remember. You might
want to talk to your your your city
council member about the Airbnb issue
because I don't think it's going to go
away.
Um, other business or announcements.
>> We do have someone online. I think it
might be uh Charles
>> and chair, members of the board. Charles
Bloom, planning development director.
Sorry about that. I was not able to make
it into the meeting in person today. Um,
Airbnbs. Yeah, we've had that as an
annual review topic a couple of
different times um in front of the
governing body and actually the city
council as well and they have um
not uh directed us to proceed with any
regulations on those. Um in talking with
other Wyoming communities, um Airbnbs
are
they're really really they take a lot of
staff and a lot of time and a lot of
resources for any type of enforcement.
Um, so they're problematic for smaller
communities that are operating on
shoestring budgets. So, we haven't been
able to move forward with that. So, that
we don't have any plans to move forward
with Airbnbs. We treat them simply as
short-term um, leases.
Um, secondly, regarding announcements
that um, we have is I don't really have
anything of substance. I defer to Aaron
and and Morgan and anyone else that's
there. And the only thing I would like
to note is we are presently
looking at a code, a unified development
text amendment that would essentially
separate uh covered carports um and
identify them as their own independent
uh structure that's different from
accessory use. This would be to set
standards for those type of structures
to allow them in other areas of the lot.
um notably provisions for sideyards and
front yards because people like to build
them um and people want to build them
and then if they ask for permission they
usually end up um being disappointed
because they can't build them where they
want them. So our goal is to create a
set of standards and a process that
would um bring them to you all the board
of adjustment for consideration.
So that's the only update that I have.
>> Thank you.
Is there a motion for adjournment? We
do.
>> Thank you. We are adjourned.